<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
               "docbook/dtd/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <title>The Music Player Daemon Sticker Database</title>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction to MPD's Sticker Database</title>
    <para>
      This document shell give a short guideline for recommended tags
      for use in MPD's Sticker Database.
      MPD's Sticker Database is a subsystem that enables users to add
      custom tags. MPD does not alter the media files.
    </para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Guideline for recommended tags</title>
    <para>
      Since there is no standard for tags in media files, this
      document is trying to give you some help deciding what tags to
      use.  The selection of these tags tries to cover the most
      widely used tags.  This way the tags might still work in other
      players, if you sync the database with your original media
      files.
      Keep in mind that we stick with lower case tags with underscores
      instead of spaces. If there will be a Sync tool in future
      its easy to change this on the fly, if needed.
    </para>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><varname>rating</varname></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Will store a rating value from 1 (worst) to 5 (best) for a
            given song.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><varname>album_rating</varname></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Will store a rating value from 1 (worst) to 5 (best) for a
            given album.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><varname>style</varname></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This tag is used to keep the Genre tag clean, by now
            having 1000's of genres.  Instead you define a Main Genre
            for each file and can make a more specific
            description. This should be one Keyword like "Post Punk"
            or "Progressive Death Metal" An Alternative name for this
            tag is "Subgenre", time will tell which one gets more
            support.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><varname>lyrics</varname></term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This one is self explaining. This gives the option to
            store lyrics of a song where they belong to: mapped to the
            song
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term><varname>similar_artists</varname> (Comma seperated list of artists)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            This tag enables a last.fm alike aproach which will still
            work when being offline Keep in mind, that this tag is
            absolutely non-standard! I am not aware of any other
            player that uses a comparable tag.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </chapter>
</book>
